二零二四年济南市九年级初中学业水平考试英语试题听力部分。第一节听录音，从每组句子中选出一个你所听到的句子，每个句子听一遍
1. The cake is delicious.
2. I haven't seen the film.
3. Did you catch the bus?
4. How tidy the room is.
5. Which one would you choose?
第二节，在录音中，你将听到五段对话。每段对话后有一个小题，从每小题
,B 6. Hi, Paul.
中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。每段对。话听两遍。
What are you going to do this weekend?
I plan to go climbing.
Hi, Paul. What are you going to do this weekend?
7. What subject are you good at,
Physics. And I dream to be an engineer.
What subject are you good at, Sam?
8. Did you enjoy the school concert last night, Alan?
Oh, yes. Everything was so wonderful.
Did you enjoy the school concert last night, Alan?
9. Mike, can't we go somewhere else to talk?
It's so noisy here.
Well, there is a park around here.
Mike, can't we go somewhere else to talk?
It's so noisy here.
Well, there is a park around here.
10. I'd like to buy a coat.
What color do you have?
We've got purple, pink, white and blue.
Well, purple is nice, but white suits me better.
I'd like to buy a coat.
What color do you have?
We've got purple, pink, white and blue.
Well, purple is nice, but white suits me better.
第三节，在录音中，你将听到一段对话。对话后有五个小题，从每小题中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。听对话前，你将有。四十秒钟的读题时间。听完后，你将有四十秒钟的答题时间。对话听两遍。
Thank you time.
Hi, Tom. Come and see my guide robot.
Oh, it looks so cool.
What is it used for, Jenny?
It's used to show the visitors around our school, and it can also introduce our
school to them.
Sounds great. How does it work then?
It's controlled by voice.
For example, when you say, where's the library?
To it, it will guide you there.
Wow, it's so smart.
How long have you worked on it?
For about a year, since I was in grade 7.
I see. You must have put a lot of efforts into it.
Yes. And I'm going to take part in the science festival.
It will start at 8 o tomorrow morning.
Would you like to come and have a look?
I'd love to, but I have to play a basketball game tomorrow.
What a pity.
Hi, Tom. Come and see my guide robot.
Oh, it looks so cool.
What is it used for, Jenny?
It's used to show the visitors around our school, and it can also introduce our
school to them.
Sounds great. How does it work then?
It's controlled by voice.
For example, when you say, where's the library?
To it, it will guide you there.
Wow, it's so smart.
How long have you worked on it?
For about a year, since I was in grade 7.
I see. You must have put a lot of efforts into it.
Yes. And I'm going to take part in the science festival.
It will start at 8 o tomorrow morning.
Would you like to come and have a look?
I'd love to, but I have to play a basketball game tomorrow.
What a pity.
Thank you. After A, B,
第四节，在录音中，你将听到一篇短文。短文后有五个小题，从每小题中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。听短文前，你将有四十秒钟的读题时间。听完后，你将有。有四十秒钟的答题时间，短文听两遍。
After Listen you have the After question.
Listen the After you answer question.
twice. Good morning, everyone.
Today, I'm going to tell you about a new children's book, called Amazing Facts.
It's written by Mary Greenwood.
She is famous for the book, Monday Blues, which was in the bookshops last year.
Greenwood's new book will be in shops this Friday.
The book is all about the planet we live on, the Earth.
Have you ever wanted to know what the longest bridge in the world is?
Or what the fastest animal is?
Well, Amazing Facts gives you the answers to these and many other questions.
The book is full of interesting information about cities, countries, sports, nature
and much more.
If you buy the book, you'll get a DVD without any cost, which shows many of the
facts in the book.
The writer has a website too.
There are lots of games and activities as well as some good ideas to help with your
schoolwork. Visit her website and join the Amazing Facts fan club, and then you will
get an Amazing Facts t -shirt.
The book is normally $13, but for this Friday only, it will be $8.
So visit your local bookshop and pick up a copy.
Good morning, everyone.
Today, I'm going to tell you about a new children's book, called Amazing Facts.
It's written by Mary Greenwood.
She is famous for the book, Monday Blues, which was in the bookshops last year.
Greenwood's new book will be in the shops this Friday.
The book is all about the planet we live on, the Earth.
Have you ever wanted to know what the longest bridge in the world is?
Or what the fastest animal is?
Well, Amazing Facts gives you the answers to these and many other questions.
The book is full of interesting information about cities,
sports, nature and much more.
If you buy the book, you'll get a DVD without any cost, which shows many of the
facts in the book.
The writer has a website too.
There are lots of games and activities as well as some good ideas to help with your
schoolwork. Visit her website and join the Amazing Facts fan club, and then you will
get an Amazing Facts t -shirt.
The book is normally $13,
but for this Friday only, it will be $8.
So visit your local bookshop and pick up a copy.